hidglobal.com 2019-11-14

# HID® Global Privacy Notice | HID Global

**Personal Data We Collect**

HID Global collects, processes, and retains information about you when you visit our websites, which may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exist pages, the files viewed on our site (e.g. HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the site. 

You may choose to provide us with additional information, such as your name, email address, company information, street address, telephone number, or other information, to access protected information on our websites or so we can follow up with you after your visit. We may combine other publicly available information related to the organization from which you work for with the information that you provide to us. HID Global or HID Global service providers may observe your activities, interactions, preferences, transactional information, and other computer and connection information (such as IP address) relating to your use of our websites and our services. 

We may also use log files, cookies and similar technologies. For more information about our use of these technologies and how to control them, see our Cookies and Similar Technologies section below. We may collect and store this information and combine this information with other Personal Data you may have provided.

If you register online on one of HID Global’s websites, we may also collect and store certain information in the aggregate about your visit automatically including: 1) internet domain and IP address from which you accessed our website 2) the date and time you access our website; and 3) the pages the you visited. We may also collect general demographic and profile data from our website from time to time. 

We may also obtain data from third parties, such as authorized distributors with which we offer services or engage in joint marketing activities. We protect data obtained from third parties according to the practices described in this Notice, plus any additional restrictions imposed by the source of the data. 

When you download mobile applications, we automatically collect technical data and related information about the devices being used for the Services, including information on the type of device you use, operating system version, application software, peripherals and the device identifier; push ID (“UDID”).

You have choices about the data we collect. When you are asked to provide Personal Data, you may decline. But if you choose not to provide data that is necessary to provide a product or feature, you may not be able to use that product or feature.

**How We Use Personal Data**

HID Global uses the data we collect to operate our business and provide you the products we offer, which includes using data to improve our products and personalize your experiences. We also may use the data to communicate with you, for example, informing you about your account and product information, to send email communications or make phone calls for the purpose of sending you information about upcoming webinars and events, product announcements, newsletters and educational content. We will use the aggregate data that we collect internally in order to better understand and assist our customers and to help improve our website and services. We process Personal Data for certain Legitimate Interests, which include some or all of the following:

  * where the processing enables us to enhance, modify, personalize or otherwise improve our services / communications for the benefit of our customers
  * to identify and prevent fraud
  * to enhance the security of our network and information systems
  * to better understand how people interact with our websites
  * to provide postal communications which we think will be of interest to you
  * to determine the effectiveness of promotional campaigns and advertising.

Whenever we process data for these purposes we will ensure that we always keep your Personal Data rights in high regard and take account of these rights. You have the right to object to this processing if you wish, and if you wish to do so please fill out a request here. Please bear in mind that if you object this may affect our ability to carry out tasks above for your benefit or to provide our products or features.

“Legitimate Interests” means HID Global’s interests in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/products and the best and most secure experience.

For example, we have an interest in making sure our marketing is relevant for you, so we may process your information to send you marketing that is tailored to you and your company’s interests. It can also apply to processing that is in your interests as well. For example, we may process your information to protect you against fraud when transacting on our website, and to ensure our websites and systems are secure.

When we process your Personal Data for our Legitimate Interests, we make sure to consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative), and your rights under data protection laws. Our legitimate business interests do not automatically override your interests - we will not use your Personal Data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent).

**Reasons We Share Personal Data**

We share your Personal Data with your consent or as necessary to complete any transaction or provide any product you have requested or authorized. In addition, we share Personal Data among ASSA ABLOY controlled affiliates and subsidiaries. We also share Personal Data with vendors or agents working on our behalf for the purposes described in this Notice. For example, companies we've hired to assist in protecting and securing our systems and services may need access to Personal Data to provide those functions and they are not allowed to use Personal Data they receive from us for any other purpose. In such cases, these companies must abide by our data privacy and security requirements and agree to any data protection agreements as we may require. 

HID Global does not sell your Personal Data to third parties. However, we may share your business contact information with our authorized distributors in order to assist you in purchasing our products or to contact you via phone or email for the purpose of marketing our products and services.

We may also disclose Personal Data as part of a corporate transaction such as a merger or sale of assets.

**Disclosure Required by Law**

HID Global may cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying users who use the website or HID Global’s products or services for illegal activities. Therefore, HID Global will respond to subpoenas, warrants, or other court orders regarding information concerning any user. HID Global will, at HID Global’s discretion, disclose information, including Personal Data, if HID Global reasonably believes that HID Global is required to do so by law, that such disclosure is necessary to protect HID Global from legal liability, or that HID Global should do so to protect the integrity of the website or the products or services.

**How to Access & Control Your Personal Data**

Upon request, HID Global will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your Personal Data. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you our products and services. Additionally, we will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

For more information on how to make an inquiry regarding the Personal Data we have about you, you may visit our GDPR personal data inquiries page.

_Opt-out preferences_

If you would like to opt-out of receiving sales and marketing communications from us, you may [update your communication preferences here](https://info.hidglobal.com/Global-Subscription-Request.html).

**Links to 3rd Party Sites**

Our website includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of HID Global. If you submit Personal Data to any of those websites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

**Cookies and Similar Technologies**

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by HID Global and our affiliates. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the website and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our site(s) or service(s). Our websites follow browser do-not-track signals.

_What are cookies_

Cookies are small pieces of text sent by your web browser by a website you visit. A cookie file is stored in your web browser and allows the Service or a third-party to recognize you and make your next visit easier and the Service more useful to you. 

Cookies can be "persistent" or "session" cookies. Persistent cookies save a file on your computer permanently. It can then be used to customize the web page as the choices and user interests. Session cookies are sent between your computer and the server to access information while you are browsing. Session cookies to not identify you personally and disappear when you turn off your browser. All of our websites use “session cookies”.

For more information on cookies generally, please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). To learn more about our use of cookies, please see the Cookie Policy tab. 

**Notice to End Users**

Many HID Global products are intended for use by organizations and are administered to you by your organization. Your use of HID Global products may be subject to your organization's policies, if any. If your organization is administering your use of HID Global’s products, please direct your privacy inquiries to your administrator. HID Global is not responsible for the privacy or security practices of our customers, which may differ from those set forth in this Privacy Notice.

**Data Security**

Wherever Personal Data is within HID Global or on its behalf, HID Global will take reasonable steps to protect the Personal Data from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. HID Global trains employees on its Information Security Policies and guidelines and makes them available to its business partners as necessary. In addition, HID Global and its business partners enter into confidentiality agreements that require that: (i) care and precautions be taken to prevent loss, misuse, or disclosure of Personal Data and (ii) any service providers only use Personal Data to perform services on behalf of HID Global.

**Transfer of Personal Data**

Our computer systems are currently based in the United States, so your Personal Data may be processed by us in the United States. If you use the website and/or services offered on the website as a visitor from outside the United States, by using the website and/or services offered on the website, you agree to this Privacy Notice and you consent to the transfer of all such information to the United States, which may not offer an equivalent level of protection of that required in the European Union or certain other countries, and to the processing of that information as described in this Privacy Notice.

The personal data that is collected and stored is exclusively used by companies within HID Global and other entities in the ASSA ABLOY group, except in the following cases where we may submit the data to third parties:

  * When required by law;
  * To a buyer or a potential future buyer of our business, and/or;
  * To the following categories of service providers appointed by HID Global who provide services connected to this website or its functions or to assist us in providing our services to customers, but only to the extent it is necessary in order to provide these services: 
    * IT service providers which host, develop or offer support

_Privacy Shield Certification_

HID Global complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework(s), as applicable) as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of customer personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. HID Global has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy notice and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/> or see our Privacy Shield Statement tab.

**Policy Changes**

This Privacy Notice may be updated from time to time as HID Global's services change and expand. We suggest that you review the Privacy Notice periodically. In the event of a material change, we will post a change notice on our website and we may notify individuals of such changes through contact information that we have for such individuals prior to the change becoming effective. If we amend the Privacy Notice, the new Notice will apply to Personal Data previously collected by HID Global only insofar as the rights of the individual affected are not reduced.

**Contact Us**

HID Global Corporation  
611 Center Ridge Drive  
Austin, TX 78753  

**How we use cookies**

Cookies we use specifically in this site are (the cookie storage time is in parentheses after its name):

  * has_js (session) - Used by the site’s framework to determine if javascript is enabled.
  * _mkto_trk - Marketo’s Munchkin JavaScript allows for tracking of end-user page visits and clicks to Marketo landing pages and external web pages.
  * STYXKEY_useractive (session) - Used by logged in users to bypass cached pages at the CDN level.
  * trwv.uid - A Marketo cookie that represents the number of times the visitor visited the website.
  * _hjIncludedInSample (session) - Used to let Hotjar know whether that visitor is included in the sample which is used to generate Heatmaps, Funnels, Recordings, etc.

We are working to improve hidglobal.com. In order to do this, we use Google Analytics, Marketo, Usabilla and Hotjar to analyze our visitors' behavior on an anonymous and aggregate level.

In addition, we allow certain third parties to install and access third-party cookies on this website. These are:

Google Analytics

The following cookies are installed by our web statistics tool Google Analytics to log information about visits and site visitors. Statistics are used to improve the use of the website by the user:

__utma (2 years)

_utmz (6 months)

_utmc (session)

_utmb (30 minutes)

_utmt (10 minutes)

_ga (2 years)

_gid (24 hours)

_gat (1 minute)

AMP_TOKEN (30 seconds to 1 year)

_gac (90 days)

Social Media Widgets

The website may use interface with social networks to allow user to post content from our website on various social platforms (Facebook, YouTube, Twitter, LinkedIn, etc.). To understand how and what information is collected and what cookies are installed by the third party, check the privacy policy of their social platform.

_What are your choices regarding cookies_

Certain countries, including members of the European Union, require your consent to the use of cookies when you visit our websites. If you access our website within one of these countries, you will be presented with information regarding your options, including the option to accept or reject certain categories of cookies. You will be able to change these settings on subsequent visits. Please note that you will not be able to opt out of receiving certain cookies that are strictly necessary for the delivery of a service requested by you. At any time when visiting our website within one of these countries, clicking on the “Cookie Preferences” link at the bottom of each page allows you to access information on cookies and change your settings.

If you do not accept cookies, your browser can be set to not automatically accept cookies from being stored or to inform you whenever a site requests storing a cookie. Previously stored cookies can also be deleted through the browser. See the help pages of your browser for more information. However, be aware that some areas or functions of our websites depend on cookies and may not work if you delete or not to accept cookies. Please contact us at [privacy@hidglobal.com](mailto:privacy@hidglobal.com) for more information about the cookies used on the website.

**Statement of Privacy Shield Participation**

HID Global’s Notice of Certification Under the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework

Effective May 16, 2018

HID Global has certified certain of our services under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework (the certification can be found [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/)).

**Scope:**

HID Global adheres to the principles of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework with respect to personal data submitted by HID Global’s direct customers and its authorized distributors (collectively, “Customers”) in reliance on the Privacy Shield where EU and Swiss customer personal data is stored or processed in our U.S. based computer systems, including our online services.

**Data processed:**

HID Global collects, processes, and retains information about you when you visit our websites, which may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exist pages, the files viewed on our site (e.g. HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the site.

You may choose to provide us with additional information, such as your name, email address, company information, street address, telephone number, or other information, to access protected information on our websites or so we can follow up with you after your visit. We may combine other publicly available information related to the organization from which you work for with the information that you provide to us. HID Global or HID Global service providers may observe your activities, interactions, preferences, transactional information, and other computer and connection information (such as IP address) relating to your use of our websites and our services.

HID Global’s computer systems are primarily based in the United States, as such, EU customer information may be transferred to these systems in order for HID Global to provide the contracted service, including card personalization services and information collected via our mobile applications.

HID Global provides online tools that our Customers use to operate aspects of their businesses. In providing these tools, HID Global processes data our Customers submit to our services or instruct us to process on their behalves. While HID Global’s Customers decide what data to submit, it typically includes information about their employees (e.g., business contact information), purchases, and billing information.

**Purposes of data processing:**

HID Global processes data submitted by Customers for the following purposes:

  * Providing HID Global’s products and services to our customers (to fulfill these purposes, HID Global may access the data to provide the services)
  * Correcting and addressing technical or service problems, or 
  * Following instructions of the HID Global Customer who submitted the data,
  * In relation to contractual requirements
  * Gaining a better understanding of how people interact with our websites
  * Improve our products and personalize your experiences
  * Informing you about your account and product information,
  * Sending email communications for the purpose of sending you information about upcoming webinars and events, product announcements, newsletters and educational content.
  * Enhancing, modifying, personalizing or otherwise improving our services and communications for the benefit of our Customers
  * Identifying and preventing fraud
  * Enhancing the security of our network, mobile applications and information systems

**Inquiries and complaints:**

If you believe HID Global maintains your personal data in one of the services within the scope of our Privacy Shield certification, you may direct any inquiries or complaints concerning our Privacy Shield compliance to [privacy@hidglobal.com](mailto:privacy@hidglobal.com). HID Global will respond within 45 days. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. If neither HID Global nor our dispute resolution provider resolves your complaint, you may have the possibility to engage in binding arbitration through the Privacy Shield Panel.

**Third parties who may receive personal data:** HID Global uses a limited number of third-party service providers to assist us in providing our services to customers. These third party providers perform database monitoring and other technical operations, assist with the transmission of data, and provide data storage services. These third parties may access, process, or store personal data in the course of providing their services. HID Global maintains contracts with these third parties restricting their access, use and disclosure of personal data in compliance with our Privacy Shield obligations, and HID Global may be liable if they fail to meet those obligations and we are responsible for the event giving rise to damage.

**Your rights to access, to limit use, and to limit disclosure:** EU individuals and Swiss individuals have rights to access personal data about them, and to limit use and disclosure of their personal data. With our Privacy Shield certification, HID Global has committed to respect those rights. If you wish to request access, to limit use, or to limit disclosure, please provide the name of the HID Global Customer who submitted your data to our services. We will refer your request to that Customer, and will support them as needed in responding to your request.

**U.S. Federal Trade Commission enforcement:** HID Global’s commitments under the Privacy Shield are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the United States Federal Trade Commission.

**Compelled disclosure:** HID Global may be required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

HID® FARGO® Connect™ Privacy Notice  
HID® Mobile Access® Application Privacy Notice  
HID® Origo™ Management Portal Privacy Notice  
HID® Origo™ Developer Community Privacy Notice  
HID® Crescendo® Mobile App Privacy Notice   
HID® Reader Manager Application Privacy Notice
